Dorothy Thompson Papers
Dorothy Thompson Papers
- "On the Record" articles
  - Typescripts
    - "Are We Driving Egypt Toward Russia?", undated (Box 95)
    - "Attempted 'Cultural Exchange" is a Flop", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "Ave, Salve, Vale!", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "Ave, Salve, Vale!" II, undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "Awakening", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "Bemoan the Death of Eve!", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "Oh, Brave New World!", undated; original typescript (Box 95)
    - "The Canadian Elections Affect the U.S.A", undated; original typescript (Box 95)
    - "The Chronology and Genesis of Oil Sabotage", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "The Coming European Revolution", undated; original typescript (Box 95)
    - "This Comment Was Solicited", undated; original typescript (Box 95)
    - "Concerning An 'Idee Fixe'", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "The Crucial Issue is Withdrawal I", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "The Crucial Issue is Withdrawal II", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "A Democracy in Wartime I", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "A Democracy in Wartime II", undated; original typescript (Box 95)
    - "A Democracy in Wartime III", undated; original typescript (Box 95)
    - "The 'Difficult' General de Gaulle", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "Discrepancies in Reports from Lebanon", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "Double Death", undated; original typescript (Box 95)
    - "The Economic Consequences of the Suez Crisis to the Middle East", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "The Economic Dilemma of Peace", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "'Eden Told Me Britain Would Not Attack Us'", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "1940 Elections", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "The Essence of Freedom is the Distribution of Power", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "The Example of Eire", undated; original typescript (Box 95)
    - "External Penetrations Have Befogged American Policy", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "The Fifth Column in Southeastern Europe", undated; original typescript (Box 95)
    - "The Forthcoming Conference", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "France Always Waits Until It Is Too Late", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "Generalizations Must Be Qualified", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "A Generation of Journalists Passes", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "The Golden Rule is Common Sense", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "A Greek Inheritance from Imperial Italy", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "The Heart of the Matter in the Adams-Goldfine Case", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "'He Made a Sinner of His Memory...'", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "The Historical Facts About 'Crusade'", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "Hot Dog! The Best We Have for the World?", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "How Liberty Goes", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "How Would It Look To You?", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "'I Did Not Anticipate That the British Would Use Force'"--Nasser, undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "If the Allies Lose", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "In a Last Appeal to Reason", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "India Believes in Tolerance", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "Indian Democracy Requires a Certain Speed of Progress", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "Israel Makes Analogies with America", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "Is a Perpetual Boom Wholly Desirable?", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "Is a Storm Brewing?", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "Is Somebody Joking?", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "It's a Lovely Island", undated; original typescript (Box 95)
    - "It's Hard to Please Indians", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "'Kilroy Was Here!'", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "Mr. Labouisse Lays Down a Burden", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "The Latitude of Tension", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "Leadership Assumed Implies Immense Responsibility", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "The Limits of Economic Plans and Military Alliances", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "Looking West from Gibraltar", undated; original typescript; 2 items (Box 95)
    - "Men and Machines", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "More Bad News from the Middle East", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "The Most Serious Implications of the Cyprus Affair", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "The Mystery of Mikolajczyk", undated; original typescript (Box 95)
    - "The 'Mystery' of Soviet Policy", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "A Nation of Suckers", undated; original typescript (Box 95)
    - "Needed Is Not Propaganda But Clarification", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "Mr. Nehru Behaves as, Being Himself, He Must", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "New York's Adolescent Gangs Mirror the Adult World", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "New York Is Not America", undated; original typescript (Box 95)
    - "No Rock 'n Roller He", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "The Norway Chapter", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "Now, Mama's Really Disgusted", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "An Ode in Time of Hesitation", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "On Death", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "On the Eve of Geneva", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "One Can Make a Few Generalizations", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "An Open Letter to the United States Government", undated; original typescript (Box 95)
    - "Policies are Determined by the Facts of Life", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "The President's Address to the U.N. Assembly", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "The Radio Network Controversy", undated; original typescript (Box 95)
    - "The Rapid Pace of History", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "Report from Inside Russia", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "Russia Turns Pragmatist As We Turn Doctrinaire", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "The Russians Do Their Homework", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "To Secretary of State Marshall", undated; original typescript (Box 95)
    - "A Self-Created Quandry", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "Setbacks Rain Upon Us From Our Natural Friends", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "'Shook Up Gangs'-or a Shook Up People?", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "The Shortcomings of the Legal Mind", undated; original typescript (Box 95)
    - "Some Further Facts and Figures", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "So We Are Not 'Prepared'?", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "And Still We Ask, Is There Danger?", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "The Stones Remember I", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "The Stones Remember II", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "Successful International Relations Require Courtesy", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "A Summit Without Summits?", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "There are Latitudes of Intensity of Feeling", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "There is Only One Way for Israel", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "'Thus Conscience Doth Make Cowards of Us All'", undated; original typescript (Box 95)
    - "Toward a New Beginning", undated; original typescript; 2 items (Box 95)
    - "To Mention One Example", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "The Tragic Dilemma of Hungary I", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "The Tragic Dilemma of Hungary II", undated; original typescript (Box 95)
    - "Unconcluded Conversation", undated; original typescript (Box 95)
    - "The Ways of Diplomacy Have Changed", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "We Hope for Full Disclosure", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "The Western Crisis is Moral", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "What is a 'Reactionary'?", undated; original typescript (Box 95)
    - "What Do You Know About Gaza?", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "What is the Condition of Syrian Armaments?", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "What is the Focus in the Brussels Fair Pavilion?", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "What is the Real Face of Syria I?", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "What is the Real Face of Syria II?", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "What Manner of Man is Nasser I?", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "What Manner of Man is Nasser II?", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "What Manner of Man is Nasser III?", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "When Greek Meets Greek", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "When is Religion Free?", undated; original typescript (Box 95)
    - "Where Dulles Speaks Only to God", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "Whither Do We Move?", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "Who Supports Gamal Abdul Nasser?", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "Why India Dislikes Military Alliances", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "Why Ph.D.'s Won't Teach", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "With or Without War, We Face the Dissolution of a Political Structure", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - "The World Is Not Divided Into Two Camps But Many", undated; typescript copy (Box 95)
    - Untitled typescripts, undated; 15 items (Box 95)
  - Published copies
    - "On the Record" published copies, 1938; 64 items (Box 96)
    - "On the Record" published copies, 1939; 118 items (Box 96)
    - "On the Record" published copies, 1940; 134 items (Box 96)
    - "On the Record" published copies, 1941; 132 items (Box 96)
    - "On the Record" published copies, 1942; 137 items (Box 96)
    - "On the Record" published copies, 1943; 133 items (Box 97)
    - "On the Record" published copies, 1944-1950; 8 items (Box 97)
    - Undated, 9 items (Box 97)
- Manuscripts
  - Manuscripts - general articles
    - "Absolute Last Appearance", original typescript (Box 98)
    - "The Age of Reason", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "Agitation for Karl Grows in Hungary", original typescript (Box 98)
    - "Alexandra Adolfovna Ismailovitch", original typescript (Box 98)
    - "All Central Europe is Turning Toward Reaction", typescript (Box 98)
    - "All the King's Horses", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "America in a New International Order", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "The American Communists and Our Foreign Policy", typescript (Box 98)
    - "American Saga", original typescript (Box 98)
    - "An American Speaks to Germans", original typescript (Box 98)
    - "An American Tragedy", original typescript (Box 98)
    - "An Open Letter to American Women", typescript copy; 12 items (Box 98)
    - "Apprehension in", 1945; original typescript (Box 98)
    - "Are We In Peril?", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "Art is Surviving in Stricken Europe", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "Auntie and the Dragon", typescript (Box 98)
    - "Aus dem schweizerschen Bundestrat", original typescript; 15 items (Box 98)
    - "The Background of the Western-Hungarian Putsch", holograph (Box 98)
    - "Back the Attack with War Bonds", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "Anatoly Barsov", holograph (Box 98)
    - "A Bath Abroad", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "The Battle of Hinterbruhl", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "Bill of Rights Sesqui-Centennial Committee", typescript copy; 6 items (Box 98)
    - Biographical sketches, holograph (Box 98)
    - "Biography of Newbold Morris", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "Both Sides of the Servant Problem", original typescript; 12 items (Box 98)
    - "The Bread Tray", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "Butter and Eggs", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "A Campaign to Dramatize a Spiritual Awakening", original typescript (Box 98)
    - "Candidates for King", original typescript (Box 98)
    - "Can We Win the Cold War?", original typescript (Box 98)
    - "The Changing Status of Women", original typescript (Box 98)
    - "College Days", typescript with corrections (Box 98)
    - "The Coming American Revolution", original typescript (Box 98)
    - "Comments on Roosevelt Navy Day Address", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "Comments on Stalin Speech", original typescript (Box 98)
    - "Concentration of Power is an Ever Corruptive Influence", holograph (Box 98)
    - "Cooperation or Chaos?", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "The Cultivated Village", holograph; 13 items (Box 98)
    - "The Danger from Russia", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "Deferred Compensation Trusts", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "De-Nazification and Man's Psychology", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "The Dilemma of the Liberal", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "Does Communism Threaten Christanity", original typescript (Box 98)
    - "A Drama of Real Life", original typescript (Box 98)
    - "Dream Your Own Millions", typescript copy; 16 items (Box 98)
    - "The Educational Crisis in America", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "Eisenhower", original typescript (Box 98)
    - "The End of German Democracy?", original typescript (Box 98)
    - "The Enigma of the Peace-Germany", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "The Entente and the Burgenland", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "Europe and America", typescript copy; 7 items (Box 98)
    - "Fascism", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "Fifth War Loan Appeal Message", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "For the Common Sense of Women", original typescript (Box 98)
    - "For the Sake of Argument", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "Founders of New Financial Dynasties" by Dorothy Thompson and M. W. Fodor, typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "Free America", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "Freedom House", typescript copy; 8 items (Box 98)
    - "German Economic Recovery Versus Chancellor Hitler", original typescript (Box 98)
    - "The German Plans as They Affect the United States", original typescript (Box 98)
    - "The German Revolution No. I", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "The German Revolution No. IV", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "The German Revolution No. V", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "The Germans Who Fought Hitler", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "Germany: An Economic Paradox", holograph (Box 98)
    - "Gertrude Geyersbach", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "Give Me Vermont", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "Good Night, Sweet Prince", typescript copy (Box 98)
    - "The Great War of Words", original typescript (Box 98)
    - "The Growth of Officialdom in Europe", holograph; 14 items (Box 98)
    - "Has Youth a Future?", original typescript (Box 99)
    - "Heartbreak House", original typescript (Box 99)
    - "History Repeats Itself", original typescript (Box 99)
    - "The Hitler Case", typescript copy (Box 99)
    - "How About a Peace Consumption Board", mimeographed (Box 99)
    - "How Democracies Meet Crisis", original typescript (Box 99)
    - "How to Give a Party and Like It", original typescript; 8 items (Box 99)
    - "The Idea of Europe", original typescript; 9 items (Box 99)
    - "I Knew a Christian", original typescript (Box 99)
    - "The Immortal Elsie", mimeographed (Box 99)
    - "An Indian Summer Rebellion", typescript copy (Box 99)
    - "Israel, Judaism, and the American Jew", typescript copy; 9 items (Box 99)
    - "The Jews and the Russian Revolution", original typescript; 1 item (Box 99)
    - "Kid Brother" by Dorothy Thompson and Victor Stoloff, original typescript (Box 99)
    - "King Carol II of Rumania at Home", original typescript (Box 99)
    - "King Zog of Albania", original typescript (Box 99)
    - "Knox of Saar-A Manona Volcano", original typescript (Box 99)
    - "General Bor Komorowski" typescript copy, 8 items (Box 99)
    - "Mr. Laski's Atom Bomb", typescript copy (Box 99)
    - "The Last Day" by Dorothy Thompson and Barbara De Porte, original typescript (Box 99)
    - "The Last Days of the Habsburgs", original typescript (Box 99)
    - "A Law to Protect the Constitution", original typescript; 5 items (Box 99)
    - "Sinclair Lewis", holograph (Box 99)
    - "The Life at the Belgrade Court", original typescript (Box 99)
    - "The Life in the Palace of the Bulgarian Tsar", original typescript (Box 99)
    - "The Life of a Columnist", original typescript (Box 99)
    - "'A Little Flat--A Strong Cognac--A Good Black Coffee'", typescript copy (Box 99)
    - "The Lure of Egypt", typescript copy; 6 items (Box 99)
    - "Make Your Own Baedecker", original typescript (Box 99)
    - "Maxim Kopf", holograph (Box 99)
    - "A Member of the Exploiting Classes", original typescript (Box 99)
    - "Memorandum on Propaganda", original typescript (Box 99)
    - "A Message to Hans", original typescript (Box 99)
    - "Military Foundation of Peace", original typescript (Box 99)
    - "Mister Eden in America", typescript copy (Box 99)
    - "The Moral and Intellectual Crisis of Our Times", original typescript (Box 99)
    - "Must There Be One Form of Democracy?", typescript copy (Box 99)
    - "My Own Foreign Policy", original typescript (Box 99)
    - "'My Red Herring'", typescript copy; 16 items (Box 99)
    - "Nazi Agent" by Kurt G. W. Ludecke, as told to Dorothy Thompson, original typescript (Box 99)
    - "A New Order for Making Democracy Pay", typescript copy (Box 99)
    - "New Vienna", original typescript; 4 items (Box 99)
    - "Ode to the Compliance Committee", original typescript (Box 100)
    - "Oh, Absalom, My Son!", original typescript (Box 100)
    - "Oh, Thou, My Austria!", original typescript (Box 100)
    - "The Old Out-Casts", original typescript; 10 items (Box 100)
    - "One World or No World--The Millenium or Bust!", holograph (Box 100)
    - "On the Condition of Civilization", original typescript (Box 100)
    - "An Open Letter to American Industrial Leaders", holograph (Box 100)
    - "An Open Letter to André Vishinsky", original typescript (Box 100)
    - "An Open Letter to Mr. Big", original typescript (Box 100)
    - "An Open Letter to the President", original typescript (Box 100)
    - "An Open Letter to the Youth of Germany", original typescript; 9 items (Box 100)
    - "Our European Policy III", original typescript (Box 100)
    - "Our Ghostly Commonwealth", holograph (Box 100)
    - "Our Ghost-ridden Government", holograph (Box 100)
    - "Outlook in Italy--Full of Danger", typescript copy; 6 items (Box 100)
    - "The Passing of the Vienna Coffee House", typescript copy (Box 100)
    - "Peace is Patriotism", typescript copy (Box 100)
    - "The Peace Movement in the United States", typescript copy (Box 100)
    - "Perfect Gentleman", original typescript; 7 items (Box 100)
    - "The Persecution of the Individual and Minorities in Nazi Germany", typescript copy (Box 100)
    - "Pertain", typescript copy (Box 100)
    - "The Pink Dress", typescript copy (Box 100)
    - "Poland in 1947", typescript copy (Box 100)
    - "A Politically Practical Program for Permanent Peace", (and accompanying documents sent to President Eisenhower) typescript copy (Box 100)
    - "Portrait of an Artist as a Woman", original typescript; 15 items (Box 100)
    - "Poverty De Luxe", typescript copy (Box 100)
    - "The Present Mind of Germany", typescript copy (Box 100)
    - "President Roosevelt", typescript copy (Box 100)
    - "Proposal for a European Settlement", original typescript; 18 items (Box 100)
    - "Reading from Left to Right--Young Men of Britain", original typescript (Box 100)
    - "Recreation", typescript copy (Box 100)
    - "Rendezvous in Berlin", typescript copy (Box 100)
    - "The Return of the Grand Manner", typescript copy (Box 100)
    - "Review of Heiden's 'Der Fuehrer'", typescript copy (Box 100)
    - "The Revival of Duelling in Hungary", typescript copy (Box 100)
    - "The Revolution Against Culture", original typescript (Box 100)
    - "The Riots in Vienna", typescript copy (Box 100)
    - "A Ruined Woman", typescript copy (Box 100)
    - "The Russian Mind--and Our Own", typescript copy; 13 items (Box 100)
    - "The Security of the Middle East", typescript copy (Box 101)
    - "The Shortcomings of Utilitarian Domination", holograph (Box 101)
    - "Signals from Germany", typescript copy; 3 items (Box 101)
    - "Silver Wedding", holograph; 3 items (Box 101)
    - "The Situation in Italy", typescript copy (Box 101)
    - "The Social and International Implications of the Nazi Revolution", original typescript (Box 101)
    - "Socialism and Americanism", typescript copy (Box 101)
    - "Socialism and Conservation", original typescript (Box 101)
    - "Softer Policy Toward Russia Forecast", original typescript (Box 101)
    - "Statement from Dorothy Thompson Regarding 'She Defends Her Country'", typescript copy (Box 101)
    - "A Still Small Voice Speaks in Vain", typescript copy (Box 101)
    - "Story of a Sunday Afternoon in Baden: Of a Fickle Friend; Of Exquisite Mary and the Woman with the Vernal", typescript copy (Box 101)
    - "The Suicide Ad", original typescript; 14 items (Box 101)
    - "Terrorism", typescript copy (Box 101)
    - "The Theory and Practice of National Socialism", typescript copy (Box 101)
    - "The Third Act", holograph (Box 101)
    - "This I Believe", original typescript; 7 items (Box 101)
    - "The Tie That Binds", typescript copy (Box 101)
    - "Those Charming Viennese", holograph (Box 101)
    - "'Thus Conscience Doth Make Cowards of Us All'", original typescript (Box 101)
    - "The Top Floor of Madam Tusson's", original typescript (Box 101)
    - "A Treasury of Democracy", typescript copy (Box 101)
    - "Try to Think", original typescript (Box 101)
    - "The Tulip Box", holograph (Box 101)
    - "A Twice-Told Tale", original typescript; 10 items (Box 101)
    - "The Ultimate Showdown with the Soviets", holograph (Box 101)
    - "Unusual Conference", typescript copy; 4 items (Box 101)
    - "The Van Doorn", original typescript (Box 101)
    - "Vitamins and the Green Plush Rabbit", typescript copy (Box 101)
    - "The Volunteer Land Corps", typescript copy; 3 items (Box 101)
    - "War and Revolution", original typescript (Box 101)
    - "The War of Words", original typescript (Box 101)
    - "The Wave of the Future", typescript copy (Box 101)
    - "Chiam Weizmann", typescript copy (Box 101)
    - "We Can Get Along with Servants", original typescript (Box 101)
    - "What Benefits Will This War Bring?", typescript copy (Box 101)
    - "What is United States Education Up To?", typescript (Box 101)
    - "What Lindbergh Really Wants", typescript copy (Box 101)
    - "What Makes War?", original typescript; 15 items (Box 101)
    - "What Should We Do With the Germans as a Whole?", original typescript (Box 101)
    - "What Should We Do About the War?", typescript copy (Box 101)
    - "Will the Next Epoch be a Matriarchy?", original typescript; 6 items (Box 101)
    - "Why Call it Post-War?", typescript copy (Box 101)
    - "Will Gangs Rule the World?", typescript copy (Box 101)
    - "Who Goes Nazi?", typescript copy (Box 101)
    - "Women Can Win the War", typescript copy (Box 101)
    - "A Wreath for Toni", original typescript; 8 items (Box 101)
    - "Yesterday and Today", typescript copy (Box 101)
    - "You Don't Know the Half of It", typescript copy (Box 101)
    - "Youth Remakes Old Europe", original typescript; 3 items (Box 101)
    - Untitled articles with subject headings
      - America and peace talks, typescript copy (Box 102)
      - America can not stand alone, typescript copy (Box 102)
      - America: how strong are we?, original typescript (Box 102)
      - America must wage peace, original typescript (Box 102)
      - American history, original typescript (Box 102)
      - American nation, typescript copy (Box 102)
      - American relief to europe, original typescript (Box 102)